# Achyuthan Unni Krishnan

PhD Candidate, 35 William Street, Apt 2D, Worcester, MA-01609 (508)-410-9993

aunnikrishnan@wpi.edu | ukachyuthan.github.io | Google Scholar

## **Research Interests**

My research is primarily focused on developing interfaces for human-robot interaction. This involves (1) developing robot control interfaces that are intuitive and efficient to use, (2) developing visual and control assistance to improve reliability and transparency of human-robot collaboration, (3) human physical and cognitive workload estimation for providing optimal assistance for remote control.

#### Education

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI), Worcester MA, US

2020-Present

PhD in Robotics Engineering

Advisor: Jane Li

Worcester Polytechnic Institute (WPI), Worcester MA, USA

2018-2020

M.S in Mechanical Engineering

Amrita University, Coimbatore, India

2012-2016

B. Tech in Mechanical Engineering

#### **Publications**

#### **Journal Articles**

- **[J4]** T.C. Lin, **A.U. Krishnan**, and Z.Li, "Perception and Action Augmentation for Teleoperation Assistance in Freeform Tele-manipulation", Submitted to ACM Transactions on Human-Robot Interaction (THRI), 2023.
- [J3] T.C. Lin, A.U. Krishnan, and Z.Li, "The Impacts of Unreliable Autonomy in Human-Robot Collaboration on Shared and Supervisory Control for Remote Manipulation", IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters(RAL), 2023.
- **[J2]** T.C. Lin, **A.U. Krishnan**, and Z. Li, "Perception-Motion Coupling in Active Telepresence: Human Behavior and Teleoperation Interface Design", ACM Transactions on Human-Robot Interaction (THRI), 2023.

**[J1]** T.C. Lin, **A.U. Krishnan**, and Z. Li, "Intuitive, Efficient and Ergonomic Tele-Nursing Robot Interfaces: Design Evaluation and Evolution", ACM Transactions on Human-Robot Interaction (THRI), 2022.

#### **Refereed Full Conference Papers**

- **[C6] A.U. Krishnan,** T.C. Lin, and Z. Li, "Human Preferred Augmented Reality Visual Cues for Remote Robot Manipulation Assistance: from Direct to Supervisory Control", Accepted by IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2023.
- [C5] T.C. Lin, A.U. Krishnan, and Z. Li, "Comparison of Haptic and Augmented Reality Visual Cues for Assisting Tele-manipulation", International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2022.
- [C4] A.U. Krishnan, T.C. Lin, and Z. Li, "Design Interface Mapping for Efficient Free-form Tele-manipulation", IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2022.
- [C3] T.C. Lin, A.U. Krishnan, and Z. Li, "How People Use Active Telepresence Cameras in Tele-manipulation", International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2021.
- [C2] T.C. Lin, A.U. Krishnan, and Z. Li, "Shared Autonomous Interface for Reducing Physical Effort in Robot Teleoperation via Human Motion Mapping", International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2020.
- [C1] T.C. Lin, A.U. Krishnan, and Z. Li, "Physical Fatigue Analysis of Assistive Robot Teleoperation via Whole Body Motion Mapping", IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), 2019.

#### **Preprints**

[C1] R. Nagpal, A.U. Krishnan, and H.Yu, "Reward engineering for object pick and place training", arXiv preprint arXiv:2001.03792 (2020).

#### **Theses**

[T1] M.S Thesis

**A.U. Krishnan,** "Nursing Robot Teleoperation via Motion Mapping Interfaces", Department of Mechanical Engineering, Worcester Polytechnic Institute, 2023

# **Work Experience**

**Robert Bosch Engineering**, Coimbatore, India 2016-2018

Associate Design Engineer, Diesel Exhaust Systems

Worcester Polytechnic Institute, Worcester, MA, USA 2021-2023

Teaching Assistant, RBE501 Robot Dynamics

#### Awards

**Best Poster Award -** WPI Graduate Research Innovation Exchange (GRIE), USA 2020

## **Academic Service**

## **Conference Paper Referee**

International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

2021-Present
International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

2021-Present

### **Technical Skills**

Programming: Python, Matlab, C, C++, C#

Libraries: OpenCV, Pandas, Tensorflow, Pytorch

System and Software: ROS, Unity, OpenAI

Design and Simulation: CATIA, Pro E, Inventor, SolidWorks